<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-17T20:45:26+01:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Collaborative Housing</title><subtitle>Together we can build homes that work for the Thames Valley
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New research report - Community Land Trust options at the Oxfordshire Cotswolds Garden Village</title><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/07/07/new-research-report-community-land-trust-options-at-the-oxfordshire-cotswolds-garden-village.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New research report - Community Land Trust options at the Oxfordshire Cotswolds Garden Village" /><published>2020-07-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-07-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/07/07/new-research-report-community-land-trust-options-at-the-oxfordshire-cotswolds-garden-village</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/07/07/new-research-report-community-land-trust-options-at-the-oxfordshire-cotswolds-garden-village.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;West Oxfordshire District Council (WODC) recently commissioned Collaborative Housing to undertake a&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.westoxon.gov.uk/media/avxefy30/community-land-trust-scoping-report-june-2020.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Exploring the options for a Community Land Trust at the Oxfordshire Cotswolds Garden Village &quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scoping report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;that looked into options for delivery and stewardship approaches for a Community Land Trust (CLT) at the Oxfordshire Cotswolds Garden Village (OCGV).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Led by Charlie Fisher, the research found a strong desire within the local community for engagement and control through establishing a CLT for long-term stewardship and ownership of assets on the OCGV site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report sets out options for CLT delivery, ownership and management at the Garden Village. Recommendations for options on ownership, identity, legal and finance include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development of a new stewardship body using the CLT legal definition found in the 2008 Housing and Regeneration Act&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incorporating ‘Village Trust’ or ‘Garden Village Trust’ into the name to establish a clear identity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensuring there is sufficient flexibility for wider community involvement beyond the OCGV site residents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The use of large-scale forms of legacy ownership to adequately meet the ‘Garden City Principles’ and ‘Garden Communities Programme Key Qualities’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incubating the CLT within partner organisations to help develop skills and administrative processes in the initial years, transitioning to independent development and management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prototyping new housing models and tenures with local cohousing groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Undertake further exploratory work on diverse long-term income streams and the impact these would have on the sitewide business plan, including the land value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborative Housing believes that these recommendations have wider implications for the delivery of CLTs on other strategic sites allocated within the adopted WODC Local Plan 2031.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From August to September 2020 WODC will undertake public consultation on the Area Action Plan for the Garden Village.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">West Oxfordshire District Council (WODC) recently commissioned Collaborative Housing to undertake a scoping report that looked into options for delivery and stewardship approaches for a Community Land Trust (CLT) at the Oxfordshire Cotswolds Garden Village (OCGV).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/capture.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/capture.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting the ball rolling…</title><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/06/05/getting-the-ball-rolling.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting the ball rolling..." /><published>2020-06-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/06/05/getting-the-ball-rolling</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/06/05/getting-the-ball-rolling.html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the 22 people from across Berkshire who came to Collaborative Housing’s &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Community-led Housing webinar&lt;/strong&gt; yesterday. Hosted by Tim Parry from Connecting Communities in Berkshire, the session was led by our Communities Lead, Fiona Brown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fiona covered topics such as what is community led housing; different models and approaches; key steps to a successful project; and where to find advice and support. Claire Milne then took us from theory to practice, talking about her experience (from the positive to the more challenging!) of developing a project with the Windsor, Ascot and Maidenhead Community Land Trust. ​A lively question and answer session followed, going into more depth on topics such as different CLH models; the Passivhaus standard; and building on Rural Exception Sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaborative Housing will be holding more of these webinars in the near future. Keep an eye on our website and social media….&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Thanks to the 22 people from across Berkshire who came to Collaborative Housing’s Introduction to Community-led Housing webinar yesterday. Hosted by Tim Parry from Connecting Communities in Berkshire, the session was led by our Communities Lead, Fiona Brown.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/simon-abrams-k_t9zj3se8k-unsplash.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/simon-abrams-k_t9zj3se8k-unsplash.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">FREE TRAINING WEBINAR- an introduction to community-led housing</title><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/05/29/free-training-webinar-an-introduction-to-community-led-housing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FREE TRAINING WEBINAR- an introduction to community-led housing" /><published>2020-05-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/05/29/free-training-webinar-an-introduction-to-community-led-housing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/05/29/free-training-webinar-an-introduction-to-community-led-housing.html">&lt;p&gt;Connecting Communities in Berkshire and Collaborative Housing Hub are running a FREE short online course on community-led housing in June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday 4th June, 11am - midday: online webinar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To book your FREE place: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ccberks.wufoo.com/forms/community-led-housing-webinar/&quot; title=&quot;https://ccberks.wufoo.com/forms/community-led-housing-webinar/&quot;&gt;https://ccberks.wufoo.com/forms/community-led-housing-webinar/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course is supported by Wokingham Borough Council Adult Community Learning. We are all aware that houses are currently being built throughout the Thames Valley on a large scale, but are they really affordable or accessible to people growing up or working in your village or community?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community-led housing is housing built on a not-for-profit basis by a community to meet its own needs. There are a number of different approaches to community-led housing, all resulting in homes built for the community but with different processes and levels of involvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This short online introductory course will enable participants to understand the differences between the various models of community-led housing. It is aimed at Parish &amp;amp; Town Councillors, land owners and anyone from both rural and urban communities interested in exploring the options for providing affordable housing for people with a connection to their community. Rural exception sites are now quite well-known and at this session we will examine them in the context of other options, including self-build, community land trusts and co-operatives.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Connecting Communities in Berkshire and Collaborative Housing Hub are running a FREE short online course on community-led housing in June.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/sticker.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/sticker.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing our Communities Lead - Fiona Brown</title><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/05/13/introducing-our-communities-lead-fiona-brown.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing our Communities Lead - Fiona Brown" /><published>2020-05-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/05/13/introducing-our-communities-lead-fiona-brown</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2020/05/13/introducing-our-communities-lead-fiona-brown.html">&lt;p&gt;Fiona has over 30 years’ experience in social housing and has worked in housing management, strategy and policy work and in enabling affordable housing development within a local authority context. She was part of the Cherwell District Council Build! Programme which provided affordable self- build opportunities for local residents and helped establish the Cherwell Community Land Trust which resulted in the Hook Norton CLT project&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Fiona has over 30 years’ experience in social housing and has worked in housing management, strategy and policy work and in enabling affordable housing development within a local authority context. She was part of the Cherwell District Council Build! Programme which provided affordable self- build opportunities for local residents and helped establish the Cherwell Community Land Trust which resulted in the Hook Norton CLT project</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk/" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>