<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-06T14:11:10+01:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//</id><title type="html">Collaborative Housing</title><subtitle>Together we can build homes that work for the Thames Valley
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Help us build People Powered Homes in Armley</title><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2018/05/08/people-powered-homes-in-armley.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Help us build People Powered Homes in Armley" /><published>2018-05-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2018/05/08/people-powered-homes-in-armley</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2018/05/08/people-powered-homes-in-armley.html">&lt;p&gt;We’re a Community Land Trust – a not-for-profit organisation that uses people power to create homes that people can afford to buy or rent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently raised £360,000 from people across Leeds to put towards our first sixteen homes in the centre of Leeds – and we’d now like to see what we could do in other parts of Leeds. Armley is top of our list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a plot of land that’s been empty for years, on Mistress Lane – and various people have looked at it over that time to see if they could build housing there.  No-one’s managed to make it work yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Council recently approached us to see if we might be able to build some homes there.  We’ve sketched out a few initial plans, and we certainly think there’s potential to build some homes that will add something different to Armley. But to make it work, we’ll need local people involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to get your thoughts.  Our “people-powered” approach only works if local people are involved from the start – that’s a big part of what can help us to make things stack up in situations where others might struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’d be interested in one day living in a home on Mistress Lane.  Or perhaps you’d like to help shape what homes on the site might look like.  Or you may be someone who can help us reach out to other people in Armley to get them interested in what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that’s you, we’d love to chat more.  Please get in touch if you’d like to find out more – and we could perhaps meet you at the site, have a cuppa somewhere in Armley, or – if you’re involved with a local community group – come along to one of your meetings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><category term="projects" /><category term="armley" /><summary type="html">We’re a Community Land Trust – a not-for-profit organisation that uses people power to create homes that people can afford to buy or rent.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/blog-image-1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Progress update on our enabler service</title><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2018/03/30/an-update-on-our-enabler-service.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Progress update on our enabler service" /><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2018/03/30/an-update-on-our-enabler-service</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2018/03/30/an-update-on-our-enabler-service.html">&lt;p&gt;Our Power to Change funded Community Led Housing enabler service is developing well. We are in touch with a number of groups in Leeds and beyond, as well as supporting other partnerships around the country to set up enabler hubs. Our workshop event on 6th March at LILAC was well attended and generated lots of ideas about how our enabler would work, as well as being full of exciting conversations with people learning from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of the groups we are in touch with include Otley CLT, a well formed group in Leeds the area with ambitions to create affordable housing in their town. There is a lot of interest from developers in the land in the area, so the CLT are busy finding out who owns land and how they might work with them. Greenwood Co-Op are a small group in the LS6 area who want to invite people to live with them and have many great ideas. We have talked with them about shaping their plans and how they might progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over in York, Yorspace are forging ahead with their plans to build affordable homes for local people as part of a larger regeneration area in their beautiful city; we are providing project management support, advice and connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will soon be choosing the three or four groups that we will work intensively with, but we will also be assisting others, with a view to work sustainably with many people over coming years to help them achieve their own plans and also move us towards our target of enabling or building 1000 homes over 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Our Power to Change funded Community Led Housing enabler service is developing well. We are in touch with a number of groups in Leeds and beyond, as well as supporting other partnerships around the country to set up enabler hubs. Our workshop event on 6th March at LILAC was well attended and generated lots of ideas about how our enabler would work, as well as being full of exciting conversations with people learning from each other.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/blog-image-1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing our new hub!</title><link href="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2017/12/18/announcing-our-new-hub.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing our new hub!" /><published>2017-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2017/12/18/announcing-our-new-hub</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//2017/12/18/announcing-our-new-hub.html">&lt;p&gt;Some great news as we being to wind down for Christmas - we can confirm that Power To Change have agreed to fund us during 2018 to establish a Community-Led Housing Hub - so that we can support more people to create People Powered Homes in Leeds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re thrilled that Power To Change have agreed to support us in this way - Leeds and Bristol are the two cities they’ve initially agreed to support. And of course it comes on the back of their £100,000 investment in us, alongside the hundreds of you who backed our People Powered Homes plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest assured, after a few days off over Christmas and New Year we’ll be straight back at it and will do all we can to make 2018 a year full of people power!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Some great news as we being to wind down for Christmas - we can confirm that Power To Change have agreed to fund us during 2018 to establish a Community-Led Housing Hub - so that we can support more people to create People Powered Homes in Leeds!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://collaborativehousing.org.uk//uploads/blog-image-1.jpg" /></entry></feed>